Koray Jimin

+90 231 536 5559 • imkorayjimin@gmail.com

Senior Full stack Engineer

I'm Koray Jimin. a passionate Front-end and full stack developer with 7+ years of experience in the software industry. I have significant experience developing complex production user interfaces for websites and web applications with modern front-end tooling such as React (React-Hooks and React-Context), Next.js, Typescript, Redux,

Material UI and Styled Component

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Full Stack Engineer Gamma • Tampa, US • 02/2022 - 07/2024

- Architectured and coded a large common code library for web applications covering areas such as security, configuration, and especially data management.
- Developed single web page applications and taught other developers to build such applications.
- Wrote many new web apps and supported many legacy apps doing architectural, coding, testing, and analysis work

Senior Full stackDeveloper Visor Finance • Brussels, Belgium • 03/2019 - 07/2022

- Built a front-end widget that is added as a single external script to an HTML page but works as a big library using vanilla JavaScript and jQuery.
- Implemented a web scrapping and browser controlling app for automated management of sites using Puppeteer and Apify.
- Optimized the front-end portion to make a fully functional and performant website using Webpack and many other compressing tools like JPEGmini.
- Implemented a real-time chatting platform-building Al-based chatbot with Socket.IO and Dialogflow.

Junior Frontend Developer blAnk • Calgary, Canada • 06/2017 - 11/2019

- Developed a single-page web app targeting mobile, that features a five-year plan tool for a startup bank. It takes into account all the user's financial aspects and decides which goals they can reach in the coming years.
- Integrated Firebase to host the application since it didn't need a back end.
- Enhanced the app with a chart (that I developed myself) that shows all expenses, debt, and goals of the user through the next five years

Internship Frontend Trainer Bitgrit • Tokyo, Japan • 06/2016 - 09/2017

- Performed troubleshooting, fixed and deployed many bug fixes for applications that were a mainsource of data for both customers and internal customer service team.
- Extensive code reviewing using GitHub pull requests, improved code quality, and conductedmeetings among peer

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Degree in Computer Science and Programming

MEF University

SKILLS

Angular, Express, Glt, GraphQL, Javascript, Javascript, jQuery, MongoDB, Node.js, React, Rest API, Typescript, Typescript, Vue